Guide to the Louis Samuel Rothschild Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Louis Samuel Rothschild papers
1953-1958
MS 425
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.5
Miscellaneous speeches and memoranda concerned with the public career of Louis S. Rothschild, particularly as under secretary of commerce for transportation in the Eisenhower administration.
Rothschild, Louis S. (Louis Samuel), 1900-1984
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Louis S. Rothschild, 1962.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Louis Samuel Rothschild: born in Leavenworth, Kansas, on March 29, 1900; received a Ph.B., Yale University, 1920; business executive with Rothschild and Sons, Inc., Kansas City, Missouri, 1920-1956; chairman, Board of Inland Waterways Corporation, 1953-1959; chairman, Federal Maritime Board of U.S. Department of Commerce, 1953-1955; under secretary of commerce for transportation, 1955-1958; president or director of other corporations and government agencies.
Scope and Contents
Miscellaneous speeches and memoranda concerned with the public career of Louis S. Rothschild, particularly as under secretary of commerce for transportation in the Eisenhower administration.
Transportation -- United States; United States -- Politics and government -- 1953-1961; Public officers; Rothschild, Louis S. (Louis Samuel), 1900-1984; United States. Department of Commerce
- Inventory
  - Papers relating to public appearances, including photographs of Schofield Barracks (trip to Hawaii, 1955) and of Louis S. Rothschild and other, unnamed dignitaries (trip to Brazil, 1956), 1953-1958 (Box 1)
  - Papers relating to public appearances, 1953-1958 (Box 2)
  - Papers relating to public appearances, 1953-1958 (Box 3)
  - Invitations, 1955-1956 (Box 3)
  - Invitations, 1955-1956 (Box 4)
  - Papers relating to the U.S. Merchant Marine Academy and maritime commerce generally, 1953-1955 (Box 5)
  - U.S. Department of Commerce: press releases, 1953-1955 (Box 6)
  - The White House, Executive Branch Liaison Office: "Fact Papers", 1954-1956 (Box 6)
  - International Labour Conference: working papers, 1958 (Box 6)
  - Transportation Council: reports, 1953-1958 (Box 7)
  - Highway Cost Allocation Study: progress report, 1957 (Box 7)